Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初のﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶｰとなった
日々人のはるか後ろから➡
Older brother Mutta continues his long quest to the moon, having finally been selected as a backup member.
月を目指し始めた兄･六太は
ついに月のﾐｯｼｮﾝに任命され➡
着実に日々人へと近づいている＞
And he's catching up to Hibito.
＜一方 月面での事故の影響で
パニック障害となり➡
A lunar accident has left Hibito struggling on the sidelines, suffering from a panic disorder.
前線から外された日々人は➡
But he's able to pass a test to return to active duty.
復帰をかけた試験を
何とか乗り越えた＞
＜しかし その先に待つ現実は
決して甘いものではなかった＞
However, he's now faced with a harsh reality.
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
#97 Won't Go Away
[TV](ﾃｨｯｼｭ)
お～う！太郎じゃねぇか！
Hey, aren't you Taro?
[TV](太郎)あっ ティッシュ先輩！
こんな所で会うなんて｡
Ah, Tissue...
Funny running into you here.
[TV]２年ぶりだなぁ太郎
しりとりでもするか！
It's been two years, Taro.
Let's play shiritori.
[TV]あ いいっすねぇ！
じゃ しりとりの｢り｣から➡
Sounds good...
Then let's start with the "ri" in "shiritori."
お願いします｡
[TV]リンボ｡
Rinbo.
[TV]リンボ？
リンボーじゃないんスか？
Rinbo?
Don't you mean "limbo"?
[TV]リンボ｡
[TV]リンボ？
Rinbo.
Rinbo?
[TV]あっ！
[TV](２人)ああ～っ！➡
ニャンボ！
[TV](笑いと拍手)
Nyanbo!
笑えねぇなら
持ってこなきゃいいのに｡
Why bring this DVD if you don't think it's funny?
ＤＶＤとか｡
だってぇ～｡
Because it's our first time spending New Year's in Houston...
ヒューストンで年越しなんて
初めてでしょう？
こっちのテレビはわかんないし
初笑いのためなら➡
I don't know what they show on TV in America.
I thought Tissue and Taro would be good for the first laugh of the year, nyanbo.
｢ティッシュ太郎ズ｣だって
持ってくるニャンボ！
[TV](ﾃｨｯｼｭ)
おい兄ちゃん これなんぼや？
Hey, Bro... Nanbo this?
[TV](太郎)なんぼって
書いてあるでしょ？
What? Can't you read?
(南波父)ニャンボ！
(アポ)ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
Nyanbo.
(父)ワンボ｡
Wanbo.
母ちゃん
買ってきた麺ってどこ？
Mom, where are the noodles we bought?
いつもの場所よ｡
ああ～ 冷凍庫か｡
In the usual place.
Oh, the fridge?
Well, I'll start frying the tempura shrimp...
さ～ 母ちゃんも
えび天 揚げるわよ～！➡
ワッショイ！
Hey-ho!
(母)♪～ はんがははんが～
ワッショイショイ
ワッショイワッショイ
Put the "tem" in the "tempura shrimp."
ぷ～らぷら
Shrimp going round and round...
ぷらんぷら～んか
Watch them bob up and down!
(母)は～いお待たせ
年越しうどん！
And here's your New Year's udon.
(一同)いただきま～す！
Let's eat!
ああ～ やっぱこれ食うと
年末って感じするな｡
The year never feels over until I've eaten these noodles...
When I learned that most people had soba rather than udon,
世間の大半の人は
蕎麦だって知った時は➡
鼻から麺が出たけどな｡
I snorted noodles from my nose.
父さんは
いつでも出せるぞ？
I can snort noodles at will.
見るか？
あ～ダメダメ お父さん！
Wanna see?
Stop that, Dad!
それは初笑いにとっといて｡
Save it for the first laugh of the year!
Right... Yeah, I'll do it later.
(父)そうか じゃあ 後で｡
見事の演奏だったな…ヒビト｡
That was a wonderful performance,
Hibito.
未だに訓練が少なくて➡
I haven't had much training to do,
練習する時間が
山ほどあったんで｡
so I've had plenty of time to practice.
このままじゃ俺➡
At this rate, I'll end up becoming a professional guitarist.
ギタリストが本業に
なっちゃいそうですね｡ハハハ｡
すまないな｡あれから二度ほど
会議をやったが ゲイツたちが…｡
I'm sorry.
There have been a couple meetings, but Gates and a few others have...
あ いや とにかく来年 年明けには
何らかの答えが出るはずだ｡➡
Well, in any case, once the new year begins, there should be a consensus.
君の次のﾐｯｼｮﾝが決定するよう
我々も最善を尽くすよ｡
We'll do the best we can to get you assigned to a new mission.
現在
おい 日々人！
Hey, Hibito...
母ちゃん達が呼んでるぞ｡
Mom and Dad are calling for us.
父ちゃんが新しいモノマネ
披露するんだと｡
Dad has a new imitation he wants to show us.
うわぁ！すごいよお父さん｡
Wow! Amazing, Dad...
ネタのレパートリー
こんなに増えたの!?
You've learned all these new imitations...
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
(父)まあな｡
(母)まあ素敵！
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
Well, yeah.
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
That's wonderful!
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
でも 下に行くほど
自信がないんだ｡
Luffy
Nagashima Yuuichi
New Imitations
Medama-oyaji
Nurikabe
Detective Conan
Lupin the 3rd
But I'm not too confident about the ones toward the bottom.
まだ練習中でな｡
I'm still working on those.
じゃあ コナンやって！
Then do Conan!
見た目は子供 頭脳は大人！
その名は 名探偵コナン！
He has the appearance of a child, but the mind of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan.
(母)うわぁ！似てる！
やだ顔そっくり～｡
Whoa, you sound just like him...
Your expression is perfect!
(父)ハハッ そうか？
(母)もっかいやって！
Really?
Do it again!
あれ？こんな所に
モノマネリストのメモがあるよ｡➡
Look, there's a list of imitations I can do!
日々人君もこっち来てみなよ！
(母)ア～ハハハッ！
Come over here, Hibito...
ほら 見た目はオッサンで
頭脳は子供の名探偵が呼んでるぞ｡
Let's go in.
The detective with an old man's appearance and a child's mind is calling you.
もうちょいしたら行くよ｡
Yeah, I'll be there in a bit.
なんだお前 何たそがれてんだ
こんな夜中に｡
What's wrong?
Why are you sitting out here, in the middle of the night?
ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
クウゥン｡
なあ ムッちゃん｡
Hey, Mu.
もしかしたら…➡
I'm not sure...
俺はもう 月に行けないかも｡
if I'll be able to return to the moon...
Eh?
最高じゃねぇか…この庭｡
Your backyard rocks.
何だっけ？それ｡
Oh, what are you doing?
ああ 昔
ＤＶＤ一緒に見たろ？
Oh, remember that movie we watched together?
こういう庭でやってるの
こうやって｡
With a guy, relaxing in his backyard, holding up his thumb?
なんか意味あんの？それ｡
Beats me.
さあ？
意味とか知らねぇけどな｡
There might not be any point.
あのな この際ハッキリ
言っとくけどな｡
Now, listen here... Let me make something clear.
俺に行けるわけねぇだろ？
I'm not going to make it there.
現在
えっ なに言ってんだよ？お前｡
What are you talking about?
もうパニック障害も
克服したんだから➡
You overcame your panic disorder, so there's nothing to worry about!
何も心配することないだろ！
俺も 最初は
そう思ってたんだよ｡
At first, that's what I thought, too.
克服すれば万事解決
また すぐ宇宙に行けるって｡➡
Once I'd recovered, everything would be normal. And I'd be back to space in no time.
だけど 全くアサインされそうな
気配がなくてさ｡
But there's no sign that I'll be assigned to a mission anytime soon.
それで…何となく気づいたんだ｡
And that's when I realized it...
俺の中から
パニック障害が消えても➡
My panic disorder may be gone,
周りの頭の中からは
消えないんだ｡
but it's still on everyone's minds.
南波日々人は パニックを起こした
宇宙飛行士っていう事実は➡
The fact that Nanba Hibito was an astronaut who had a panic attack
もう 消せねぇんだよ｡
just won't go away.
い いや んにゃあ
そんなことはないと思うけど…｡
N-No...
I don't think that's true...
Uh...
ええっと…｡
室長は
味方してくれてるけどね｡
The chief is on my side.
《なんか…
なんか言ってやらねぇと！》
I have to...
I have to say something!
《兄として こんな時こそ！》
In this situation, that's the older brother's duty!
《なんか…》
What do I say?
さて…｡
Well...
父ちゃんのモノマネでも
見に行くか ムッちゃん｡
Let's go watch Dad do his imitations, Mu.
えっ？ああ…｡
Yeah...
おおっと あけました｡
おめでとう｡
Oh, it's after midnight.
Happy New Year.
おお おめでとう｡
Yeah, Happy New Year.
Damn it!
チッキショーッ!!
January 4, 2028
あれ？日々人は？
Huh? Where's Hibito?
He already left in a "whoosh."
先に行ったわよ サーッて｡
(母)それよりムッちゃん｡
Anyway, Mu...
今日から母ちゃんたちね
ラスベガス行って➡
Beginning today,
your dad and I will be going to Las Vegas to hit the jackpot at the casinos.
カジノで
ひと儲けしてくるから｡➡
で あさっては
グランドキャニオン行って➡
Two days later, we'll be enjoying nature's majesty in the Grand Canyon, as your dad recites a haiku.
地球の壮大さを感じたところで
多分 お父さんが一句詠むから｡
デカいかも
グランドキャニオン 日本より｡
"I think it is big.
This is the Grand Canyon here.
With love from Japan."
その後はロサンゼルス行って
チャイニーズシアター見て➡
After that, we'll go to Los Angeles, and visit the Chinese Theater,
ハリウッドの
あのでっかい看板をバックに➡
and we'll take a picture with the Hollywood sign behind us.
記念写真撮るのよね｡
で どっかでステーキ食べて
お肉も～無理ってなったら➡
And then, we'll load up on steak until we're sick of eating meat,
before returning to Japan.
日本に帰るわ｡
《ああ…》
(せりか)南波さ～ん！
Nanba!
おはようございます｡
Good morning!
あれ？おはよう｡
せりかさんもキャプコムの訓練？
Oh, good morning.
Are you also here for CAPCOM training, Serika?
そうなんですよ
今日からＩＳＳの管制室入りです｡
That's right.
I'll be in the ISS mission control center for a while.
南波さんは月の方ですか？
You'll be in the lunar MCC?
そ そうなんだよね｡
すぐ隣の管制室｡
Y-Yeah, I'll be in the MCC next to yours.
《すんごい！
うれしいぞ これは！》
Wow! This is great news!
《これから しょっちゅう
せりかさんに会えるではないか》
I'll run into Serika all the time!
《近いからお昼とか誘っても
すっごく自然！あ あれ？》
Inviting her to lunch will be a breeze for me.
《バトラー室長？》
Chief Butler?
《なに話してんだろ？》
What are they arguing about?
とにかく！
これが最後の会議だ｡
I'm saying that this will be the last meeting.
最後ぐらい出席してくれ｡
Can you show up this time?
はぁ…わかったよ 仕方ない｡
Fine, have it your way.
だが 結果は変わらんぞ
バトラー｡
But nothing will change, Butler.
これが済んだら
ナンバ･ヒビトの事は もう忘れろ｡
Once this is over, it'll be time to forget about Nanba Hibito.
Nanba.
南波さん！
何か考え事ですか？
珍しく真剣な顔ですね｡
Is there something on your mind?
You usually don't look so serious.
いや いやいや はははっ｡
O-Oh...
I think I had something on my mind, but I forgot what it was.
何か考えてたような気もするけど
忘れちゃった！
あらっ…｡
っていうか俺 真剣な顔が
珍しかったとは…｡
Oh, no.
And you were saying that I don't usually look serious?
心はいつでも真剣だよ｡
But on the inside, I'm always serious.
ああ いや…
あ～っ ごめんなさい｡
Oh, um... Sorry about that.
間違えました｡深刻な顔って
言おうとしたんです｡
That came out wrong.
I meant to say you don't usually look so grim.
I think I'm okay.
とりあえず大丈夫だよ｡
ありがとう せりかさん｡
Thanks, Serika.
I'll see you later, then.
それじゃあ また｡
Yes.
は はいっ｡
よし やるか！
Okay, let's get to work!
失礼します！
Excuse me!
Simulation Mission Control Center
よくさ ニュース番組の海外からの
生中継なんかであるだろ｡➡
Have you seen on the news when they have reporters in different countries?
スタジオとのやりとりで
リポーターの返答が➡
While they're waiting for the reporter to respond, there's a slight delay.
ちょっと遅れるあれ｡
ああ～ あるね｡
Yeah, I know what you mean.
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)エジプトのキャシーさん｡
Let's go to Cathy in Egypt.
(ｷｬｽﾀｰ)キャシーさん？
[TV](ｷｬｼｰ)はい こちら…あ はい！
Cathy, can you hear us?
Yes, then...
Yes.
なんか 相手と声がかぶっちゃって
お互い引いたり またかぶったり➡
They end up talking at the same time, and interrupting each other.
And it turns into chaos.
ぐだぐだになっちゃう あれね｡
Yeah, that's right.
月と地球の交信でも
それと同じ事がよく起こるんだよ｡
During communication between the moon and Earth, the same thing happens all the time.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)月との交信タイムラグは
約２.５秒｡➡
When communicating with the moon, there's about a 2.5-second lag.
After you finish speaking, it's important to wait patiently for a response.
用件を伝え終えたら 慌てず
相手の返答を待つ事が大事だ｡➡
交信がかぶって
会話を打ち消し合うのは➡
If both sides speak at once, there can be serious damage to the mission.
ミッション進行の妨げになるし
飛行士のストレスにも➡
And it can cause stress for the astronauts, which is a serious concern.
繋がるから要注意だ｡
なるほど｡
I see.
キャプコム
アルタイル着陸にむけて➡
CAPCOM...
Instruct Moonbase to use Gibson's camera to confirm the Altair landing site is clear.
着陸ポイントが
クリアになっているか➡
ギブソンのカメラで確認するよう
ムーンベースに伝えてくれ｡
了解！
Roger that.
本番でも毎回やる工程だよ｡
ＯＫ｡
During real landings, this is standard procedure.
Okay.
《あれ？言わねぇの？》
Huh?
Why isn't he saying anything?
話しかけるタイミングにも
配慮が必要だ｡➡
It's important to wait for the right time to talk to them.
作業中のクルーに話して
負担をかける場合もあるし➡
If you distract the crew while they're working, it could cause problems.
逆に機を逃して伝えられないまま
すれ違いが生じることもある｡
But you also need to worry about missing the right time to communicate things.
こちらヒューストン
ダミアンだ｡➡
This is Houston... It's Damian.
間もなくアルタイルが
月周回軌道から着陸ポイントに➡
Altair is about to initiate steps to leave lunar orbit and land on the surface.
降りるためのステップに入る｡
着陸対応マニュアル➡
In accordance with step 7-12 of the landing manual,
ステップ７－１２｡ギブソンによる
着陸ポイントの確認をしてくれ｡
have Gibson check the landing site.
Check the landing site.
[TV]着陸ポイントの確認をしてくれ｡
[TV](飛行士)了解！
ステップ７－１２➡
Roger that.
In accordance with step 7-12,
ギブソンによる
着陸ポイントの確認を開始する｡
we'll use Gibson to check the landing site.
てな具合だ｡
スムーズ！さすがダミアン｡
Like that.
That was smooth.
You're good, Damian.
訓練用の別回線に繋げば➡
If we switch to the line used for simulations,
着陸船アルタイルのシミｭレｰタｰで
訓練中のビンスと通話ができる｡
we can speak to Vince in the Altair simulator.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)１０分後に
通話訓練開始だ ムッタ｡➡
In ten minutes, we'll begin your training, Mutta.
You'll be communicating with Vince, as he attempts to land on the moon.
アルタイル内のビンスと
月面着陸時のやりとりを➡
してもらおう｡
了解！
Roger that.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)なんのための試験だったと
思ってる！➡
What did you think that test was for?
ヒビトを救うためだ！
It was meant to help Hibito!
そして彼は見事それに合格した！
And he passed the test!
なのに なんでミッションへの
任命許可が下りないんだ！
So why hasn't he been assigned to a new mission?
それはミスター･ヒビトが
パニック障害になったからだ｡
Because Mr. Hibito has suffered from a panic disorder.
だからっ！それは あの試験で
克服した事を確認しただろ！
But the test proved that he's overcome that disorder!
彼が克服できたのはプールの中だ｡
月面じゃない｡
The test was performed in a pool, not on the moon.
それを言ってしまったら…｡
月面で発作は起こらないと
断言できるのか？
If you go there...
Can you guarantee that he won't suffer an attack while he's on the moon?
発作の確率はゼロではない｡
それは君も認めるな？
It's still possible that an attack will occur.
You can't deny that.
Chief Butler, I believe there's a saying for this.
(ｹﾞｲﾂ)バトラー室長｡
よく言う例えがあるだろう｡
樽いっぱいのワインに
スプーン１杯の汚水を注ぐと…➡
If you add one spoon of dirty water to a barrel of wine,
それは樽いっぱいの汚水になる｡
the entire barrel will be full of dirty water.
今のヒビトが
汚水だとでも言う気か！
Are you comparing Hibito to dirty water?
いや 悪いがバトラー➡
No.
I'm sorry, Butler. But what he represents is much worse.
彼の中にあるのは
汚水どころではない｡
He's poison.
(ゲイツ)毒だよ｡➡
You're adding a spoon of poison to a barrel of wine.
樽いっぱいのワインの中に
スプーン１杯の毒｡➡
If someone told you to drink from the barrel,
もう飲んでも大丈夫ですよと
言われたところで➡
would you do it?
君なら飲むか？そんなワインを｡
(ゲイツ)飲めるワインは 他にも
あるんだ バトラー｡➡
There's other wine around, Butler.
わざわざ毒入りを選ぶ理由が
どこにある｡
Why choose wine that's been poisoned?
アルタイル ビンスさん｡
こちらヒューストン➡
Altair, Vince...
This is Houston. It's Nanba Mutta.
続けてナンバ ムッタです｡
It's Nanba Mutta.
続けてナンバ ムッタです｡➡
In accordance with landing manual step 3-1, please begin the preliminary landing procedure.
月面着陸マニュアル
ステップ３－１に沿って➡
着陸に向けた作業を始めて下さい｡
(ビンス)了解｡
Roger that.
[TV]ステップ３－１に沿って
作業を開始する｡
According to step 3-1, we will begin the landing procedure.
ステップ３－１０まで
完了次第連絡する｡
We will contact you once step 3-10 is complete.
Okay... That was good, Mutta.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)よ～し ＯＫだ ムッタ｡
ここまでいい調子！
All good so far!
いやぁ～ フフフ…｡
Heh, maybe I'm actually good at this stuff.
もしかしたらこういうの
得意なのかも…僕｡
失礼します｡
Excuse me...
とりあえず 座って話そうか｡
Have a seat, and let's talk.
There has to be a way.
《なんとかなるもんだ》
(強盗)な…なんだ!?あっ！
Wh-What's going on?!
うわわわっ！ああ～っ!!
現在
《かつての
どうしようもなかった➡
At one point, I'd hit rock bottom.
ナサ
あの俺が…今はＮＡＳＡの
管制室なんかで座ってる》
And now, I'm sitting in a NASA mission control center.
《当時は不可能だと思ってた
ような事が 今は出来てるんだ》
At the time, I thought it was impossible, but here I am.
《そうだ｡日々人だって
なんとかなるはずなんだ！》
Yeah...
Hibito will find a way!
大丈夫ですよ｡バトラーさん｡
It's okay, Butler...
こうなる予感はありました｡
I had a feeling this would happen.
俺はもう 宇宙へ行けないって…｡
Somehow, I knew I wouldn't be going back to space...
そんな気はしてました｡
(バトラー)《ロナルド…》
Ronaldo...
(バトラー)《ロナルド！》
《私は あの夜に何も言えなかった
自分を恥じて➡
I was ashamed I couldn't tell Hibito anything when we last spoke.
出まかせでもいいから
日々人に一言｢なんとかなる｣と➡
So I decided to tell him that things would work out, whether or not I believed it.
言ってやろうと決めたのだが…》
《どうやらその判断が遅すぎた》
But it appears that I was too late.
《私は 何も伝えられずに》
I missed my chance...
お～い 日々人ぉ～い｡
Hey, Hibito.
《その機を逃してしまった》
...to say something.
《あれ…》
Huh?
＜次の日の朝…
日々人は姿を消した＞
The next morning,
Hibito was gone.
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#98 The Ultimate Astronaut
With Hibito's disappearance, I learn the truth.
＜日々人が姿を消した中
私は ある事実を知る＞
After passing his test,
＜復帰試験に合格したはずの
日々人は➡
Hibito received an unexpected label.
思いも寄らぬ決定を
突きつけられていた＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"The Ultimate Astronaut"